goalbookapp.com 2016-11-14

# » Privacy | Success for Every Student

#### Privacy Policy

Welcome, and thank you for your interest in Enome, Inc. (“Enome” “us” or “we”) and Goalbook, our web-based network that provides functionality for teams of educators, parents, and students to collaborate around student personal learning plans, and provides a toolkit for organizations such as schools to personalize learning plans and resources to their individual students’ needs (collectively, the “Services”), as further described in the Goalbook Terms of Use.

This Privacy Policy describes the information that we gather from you, how we use and disclose your information, and the steps we take to protect your information. By using the Services, you consent to the privacy practices described in this policy.

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and is subject to the Goalbook [Terms of Use](https://goalbookapp.com/terms). Capitalized terms that are not defined in the Privacy Policy have the meaning given to them in the Terms of Use.

#### Our Commitment to Children’s Privacy:

Protecting the privacy of children is important to us and we are committed to compliance with the Federal Trade Commission’s rules implementing the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). Persons under the age of 13 (herein referred to as “Minors”), may only use the Services and disclose personally identifiable information to us when: (i) Enome has contracted with the organization  through which the Minor gains access to the Services (the “Contracting Organization”) to provide the Services for the use and benefit of the Contracting Organization, and for no other purpose, and (ii) the Contracting Organization, with full notice of our collection, use and disclosure practices as described in this Privacy Policy, has authorized us to collect a Minor’s personally identifiable information through the Services. The Contracting Organization’s authorization to us is based upon the Contracting Organization having obtained consent from the Minor’s parent or guardian.

If we gain knowledge that we have collected personally identifiable information from a Minor without parental consent we will remove that information from the Services as quickly as possible. If you are under the age of 13 and do not have a valid Goalbook account, do not send us any personal information, such as through e-mail or otherwise. If you believe that a child under the age of 13 has sent us personal information without parental consent, please contact us at privacy@goalbookapp.com.

#### The information that we collect:

  * User-provided Information. When you use the Services you may provide and we may collect what is generally called “personally identifiable” information, such as your name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number, and demographic information. For example, you may provide us with personally identifiable information when you register for an account, post User Content, interact with other users of the Services through communication or messaging features, or send us customer service related requests. When you buy products or services from us, we may ask you for your credit or debit card number, type, expiration date, and similar information. Such information is collected and stored by our third-party payment processing company, and use of such information is governed by such company’s applicable terms of service and privacy policy.
  * Information from other Users. We may receive information, including personally identifiable information, from other users of the Services. For example, we may receive personally identifiable information about a student when a  Contracting Organization uploads that student’s “Personal Education Plan.” We protect this personally identifiable information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
  * “Cookies” Information. When you use the Services, we may send one or more cookies – small text files containing a string of alphanumeric characters – to your computer. We may use both session cookies and persistent cookies. A session cookie disappears after you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to our website. Persistent cookies can be removed. Please review your web browser “Help” file to learn the proper way to modify your cookie settings. Please note that if you delete, or choose not to accept, cookies, you may not be able to utilize the features of the Services to their fullest potential.
  * “Automatically Collected” Information. When you use the Services or open one of our HTML e-mails, we may automatically record certain information from your web browser by using different types of technology, including “clear gifs” or “web beacons.” This “automatically collected” information may include your IP address or other device address or ID, web browser and/or device type, the web pages or sites that you visit just before or just after our website, the pages you view on the Services, and the dates and times that you access the Services. This information is gathered for all users.
  * Information Provided By Contracting Organizations. We may also receive information, including personally identifiable information, under our agreements with Contracting Organizations. It is the responsibility of the Contracting Organization to comply with all laws related to the disclosure of such information. For example, this personally identifiable information may include the educational records of students. It is the responsibility of the Contracting Organization to comply with the Federal Educational Rights Privacy Act (FERPA) and all state privacy laws and other laws. Once this information is in our possession, we will protect it in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

#### How we use the information we collect:

  * We use the information that you provide or that we collect, to operate, maintain, enhance and provide all of the features of the Services.
  * We will use all of the information that you provide of that we collect to understand and analyze the usages trends and preferences of our users, to improve the Services, and to create new features and functionality.
  * We may use your e-mail address or other personal information (a) to contact you for administrative purposes such as customer service, to address intellectual property infringement, right of privacy violations or defamation issues related to your User Content posted on the Services or (b) to forward you messages sent to you by other users of the Services and send you other messages related to the Services. Generally, you have the ability to opt-out of receiving any such communications, either through links provided in the messages or by updating your account preferences through the Services.
  * We may use “cookies” information and “automatically collected” information to: (a) personalize our services, such as remembering your information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit our website; (b) monitor and analyze the effectiveness of Service; and (c) monitor aggregate site usage metrics such as total number of visitors and pages viewed.

#### When we disclose information:

  * Your privacy is very important to us, and we are not in the business of selling your information.
  * Any information, including personally identifiable information, that you voluntarily choose to include in an area of the Services accessible to other users, such as a profile page, a message to another user, or in User Content, will be available to anyone who has access to that content, including other users. Once you make your personally identifiable information available in this way, it may be collected and used by the recipients..
  * We work with third-party service providers to provide website and application development, hosting, maintenance, and other services for us related to the operation of the Services. To the extent it is necessary for these third-party service providers to complete their contractual obligations to us, these third parties may have access to or process your personally identifiable information. These disclosures are made under terms comparable to this policy, and the recipients are limited to using the information the purpose for which it was provided.
  * We make certain automatically collected and other aggregate non-personally-identifiable information available to third parties, to: (i) comply with various reporting obligations; (ii) for business or marketing purposes; or (iii) to assist such parties in understanding our users’ interests, habits, and usage patterns for certain programs, content, services, advertisements, promotions, and/or functionality available through the Services.
  * We may also disclose your information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with state and federal laws (such as U.S. Copyright law), in response to a court order, judicial or other government subpoena or warrant, or to otherwise cooperate with law enforcement activity.
  * We also reserve the right to disclose your information when we believe, in good faith, that disclosure is appropriate or necessary to take precautions against liability; to protect us and others from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses or activity; to investigate and defend ourselves against any third party claims or allegations; to assist government enforcement agencies; to protect the security or integrity of us and the Services; or to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Enome, our users, or others.

#### Your Choices:

You may, of course, decline to share certain personally identifiable information with us, in which case we may not be able to provide to you some of the features and functionality of the Services. You may update or correct your profile information and preferences at any time by accessing your account preferences page through the Services. You may request deletion of your account, including all profile information and any library data you stored on our system, by writing an email request from your email account to support@goalbookapp.com. Please note that while your changes are reflected promptly in active user databases, we may retain information you submit for a variety of purposes, including backups and archiving, prevention of fraud and abuse, and analytics.

#### Third Party Services:

Our website may contain links to Web sites and services provided by third parties including links contained in User Content. Any personally identifiable information you provide on third party sites or services is provided directly to that third party and is subject to that third party’s policies, if any, governing privacy and security. We are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices and policies of third party sites or services to which links are displayed on our website. We encourage you to learn about third parties’ privacy and security policies before providing them with personally identifiable information.

#### Our Commitment to Data Security:

We use commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of your personally identifiable information. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission of information, we make commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of our systems. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. If we learn of a security systems breach, then we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. We may post a notice through our website if a security breach occurs. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive a free written notice of a security breach you should notify us at privacy@goalbookapp.com.

#### International Visitors:

The website and Services are hosted in the United States. If you choose to use the Services from the European Union or other regions of the world with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, then please note that you are transferring your personally identifiable information outside of those regions to the United States and by providing your personally identifiable information on the Services you consent to that transfer.

#### In the Event of Merger or Sale or Bankruptcy:

In the event that all or a portion of Enome, Inc. or its assets are acquired by or merged with a third party entity, we reserve the right, in any of these circumstances, to transfer or assign the information that we have collected from users in connection with such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control. In the event that Enome goes into bankruptcy under Chapter 11, your personally identifiable information and library data will be deleted from our system.

#### Changes and Updates to this Privacy Policy:

Please revisit this page periodically to stay aware of any changes to this Privacy Policy, which may be revised periodically at our sole discretion, as provided in Terms of Use. If we modify the Privacy Policy, we will make it available through the website, and indicate the date of the latest revision. In the event that the modifications materially alter your rights or obligations hereunder we will make reasonable efforts to notify you of the change. For example, we may send a message to your e-mail address, if we have one on file, or generate a pop-up or similar notification when you access the Services for the first time after such material changes are made. Our amended Privacy Policy will automatically take effect 30 days after it is made available through the website, except that (i) we generally only use your personally identifiable information in the manner described in the Privacy Policy in effect when we received that information and (ii) if you do not agree with any changes to the Privacy Policy, you may terminate your account and stop using of the Services. Your continued use of the Services after revised Privacy Policy has become effective indicates that you have read, understood and agreed to the current version of the Privacy Policy.

#### Our Contact Information:

Please contact us with any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, your personally identifiable information, our use and disclosure practices, or your consent choices by e-mail at privacy@goalbookapp.com.

Enome, Inc. (Goalbook)  
PO Box 1289  
San Mateo, CA 94401
